Kushal Singh Thakur

Email: singhkushal937@gmail.com https://github.com/Kush026 Mobile: +91 9498073574

Summary

Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing a large and complex web application. Ability to troubleshoot problems and automate tasks. Built applications from ground zero and seen it through all phase of development cycles.

EXPERTISE

Web Development Object-oriented Programming Design Patterns Test-driven Development Troubleshooting & Optimization Responsive Web Design

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

Chennai, India

B. Tech in Aerospace and M. Tech in Applied Mechanics

July 2011 - April 2016

Experience

FP Tech Science Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, India

Software Development Engineer

Dec 2017 - Present

- Search Application: Extensively worked on search system. Designed a REST service to search based on multiple filters and category. Implemented dynamic price range facet.
- Category Hierarchies: Built a REST service solely which was responsible for storing and manipulating category hierarchically data and metadata.
- Auto Suggest: Redesigned the application to make it multi-lingual.

Tech: Java, Spring, Spring boot, Hibernate, MySQL, Apache Solr, Maven, Gradle

ZenParent Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, India

Software Developer

July 2016 - Oct 2017

- User Generated Content: Developed an application which allows users to publish articles on the website.
- Website Revamp: Revamped website and was solely responsible for Backend development.
- Automation: Implemented algorithm for automating the distribution of personalized newsletters, email notifications and data sheet generation.
- Apache Solr: Integrated Apache Solr with Wordpress to speed up the content search across the website.
- Troubleshooting & Performance: Troubleshoot the site performance issues using New Relic.
- AMP pages: Designed Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMPs) to enhance mobile user experience.

Tech: WordPress, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Apache Solr, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JSON, Git

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming/Scripting: Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP, SQL.

Web: Spring, Spring Boot, REST, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JSON

Data Stores: MySQL, Apache Solr

Miscellaneous: Git, Maven, Gradle, Linux, Unix

Projects

- Boggle Word Game: Designed Boggle word game in Java language.
- Seam-carving: Seam-carving is a content-aware image resizing technique where the image is reduced in size by one pixel of height (or width) at a time